roomandboard.com 2019-02-24

# Privacy Policy - Our Website - Room & Board

Room & Board, Inc. is committed to respecting your private information and protecting it from misuse. Our Privacy Policy outlines our current policy on personally identifiable information concerning consumers, and covers the operations of our stores, our catalog and telephone sales, and within our Web site. We encourage you to read it whenever you visit our stores, catalogs or Web site, since we may change this policy from time to time due to enhancements to our systems or changes in the law. A copy of the current policy is always posted at [www.roomandboard.com/privacy/](https://www.roomandboard.com/privacy/). You may also obtain a copy of the current policy by contacting the office of the Privacy Officer shown at the end of this policy. 

**By submitting your personal information to us, you are consenting to the collection and processing of your personal information in the United States and to our use of your personal information and any related information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. If you are submitting personal information of third parties to us, you warrant and represent you have their consent to provide their personal information to us and you will indemnify us and hold us harmless from and against claims by such individuals relating to our processing and use of such personal information within the terms of this Privacy Policy.**

## Basic Privacy Principles

The following "Basic Privacy Principles" apply throughout our entire enterprise, whether we gather information through our stores, our catalog operations, or our Web site. 

Room & Board collects the following categories of personally identifiable information through our Website, our stores, and our catalog operations: name, address, telephone number, and email address. We may collect your personally identifiable information across various devices you may use to access our website, like a mobile device, PC, or tablet, for example, and from our stores and catalog operations. You may submit your credit card or financial account information to complete a purchase on our web site. While Room & Board does not store or save credit card or financial account information, it or its third party vendors use credit card or financial information you provide to process purchase transaction(s). 

We may also obtain information such as name, and we may obtain data such as image, voice, signature, statements and quotes, stories or anecdotes, personal or commercial attributes or identifying features, interior or exterior photographs, videos, or other depictions of premises, home or office, images of family, friends, or pets, stories, commercial attributes or identifying features (collectively "Media") from individuals who send us such material or in connection with agreements with individuals. We may use Media for any lawful purpose, and Media is not considered personally identifiable information for purposes of this Privacy Policy. 

We do not consider all information that we may gather or create in operating our business to be personally identifiable information. If information is not identity information or directly associated with identity information, we do not consider it to be personally identifiable information. For example, a database of our customers' purchases in aggregate which does not identify the individual customers would not be personally identifiable information. 

We will use your personally identifiable information which we learn through our interactions with you only for the purposes you would reasonably anticipate us doing. This includes, but is not limited to, use to contact you to answer your questions, to fulfill orders, to obtain billing or payment information, to follow-up on prior orders or respond to your comments to ensure your satisfaction, and to contact you with additional information where you have permitted us to do so. 

**We do not share, sell or trade your personally identifiable information with third parties, except we may share some of your personally identifiable information with third party service providers as specified below.**

We may disclose some of your personally identifiable information to one or more of our own service providers that we may use to fulfill services for you. We will reasonably assure that those service providers are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, implement and maintain reasonable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information, to protect the personal information from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure, and only use or disclose it for the purposes we hire them for or law enforcement purposes. You may also disclose some of your personally identifiable information directly to one or more of our own service providers that we may use to fulfill services for you. We will reasonably assure that those service providers are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, implement and maintain reasonable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information, to protect the personal information from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure, and only use or disclose it for the purposes we hire them for or law enforcement purposes. If you provide any personally identifiable information to us as part of a sweepstakes or contest entry, we may disclose such information to any third party service providers, sponsors or co-sponsors of the sweepstakes or contest. In that case, when you enter a contest or sweepstakes, you may become subject to the privacy policy of these parties in addition to this Privacy Policy. We may also disclose personally identifiable information to others if we are required to do so by law, to protect and defend the rights of Room & Board, Inc., or in the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event. 

The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us. Although we cannot guarantee against loss, misuse, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or destruction of data, we use commercially reasonable security measures to protect you from such occurrences. If necessary in accordance with the law, we will disclose to you any known or reasonably suspected breach in security involving your personally identifiable information. 

This Privacy Policy is intended to comply with applicable United States laws and regulations, including the laws of particular states where our stores or customers are located. Our stores are located in the United States, all catalog orders are placed to our operators located in the United States, and our Web site is targeted only to residents of the United States. If you are not a resident of the United States, please note that our information gathering practices may not be compliant with your own country's laws and regulations, and you should not share your personally identifiable information with us unless you are willing and able to be subject to United States laws concerning such disclosures. 

## Store and Catalog Operations

In addition to the Basic Privacy Principles discussed above, the following policies apply specifically to our Stores and our Catalog operations. 

Our stores and catalog operations are available to you to discuss our products and services with a Design Associate, and you may place your orders through one of our Design Associates in the stores, or place a catalog order via postal mail or via telephone. When we take your order, we will obtain some of your personally identifiable information including your payment information. We will only use that personally identifiable information from your order for purposes concerning the fulfillment of your order. In doing so, your personally identifiable information from an order may be used or shared among our different offices, representatives or service providers such as the store, our catalog sales offices, our warehouses, our headquarters, the manufacturers of products you have purchased, the freight carriers used to deliver products to you, installers or designers we have engaged to assist with your order, or our credit card merchant banks or other bankers. We will share only that portion of your personally identifiable information with third parties that is reasonably required to fulfill your order, and those third parties will be contractually obligated to use the personally identifiable information only for order-fulfillment purposes. 

We will comply with our credit card merchant banks' requirements for the use and storage of your credit card information, such as obligations concerning the security of your credit card numbers, as well as any laws that apply to that information's use and storage. 

## Web Site

In addition to the Basic Privacy Principles discussed above, the following policies apply specifically to our Web site ([roomandboard.com](https://www.roomandboard.com/)). 

Our Web site allows you to shop our catalog and place orders by use of an e-commerce system that may be provided, in whole or in part, by one or more third party e-commerce providers. The portions of our Web site that allow you to place an order by giving your personal information use industry standard encryption methods such as secure-socket layer ('HTTPS') technology to protect your information while in transit between your computer, our computers, and our third party e-commerce providers' systems. Also, all of your sensitive personal information (for example your credit card data and your order information) is encrypted while it is being processed and stored by us and our third party e-commerce providers. Once your order has been received by us, we then process and fulfill your order using our normal catalog ordering system subject to the privacy policies described above. Our third party e-commerce providers are under contract with us to maintain the confidentiality and security of your sensitive personal information, and not to use it for any purpose other than assisting with the transactions in your own orders. 

Our Web site gives you the option to create a personal account. To create an account, you will be asked to provide contact information and select a username and password. This personally identifiable information may be used to provide you with personal services from us. You may also use the account to use our online personalized features. However, other than when submitting an order to purchase from our Web site, submitting contact information and creating an account are strictly voluntary and are not required to use our Web site. As a way to enhance our ability to protect your private information, we do not provide you with the ability to store your credit card (or similar) data on our Web site for future transactions, and we ask that you re-enter that information each time you place an order with us. 

Our Web site is not targeted to persons under the age of 13, and is not permitted to be accessed by children under 13. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from persons under age 13. 

Anonymous, non-personally identifiable information such as your IP address, domain server, type of computer or device, type of web browser, and addresses of referring site, also known as traffic data, may be collected and used for web analytics, to approximate a user's location, monitor fraudulent orders, and to diagnose problems with our server and administer our site. We may have functionality on our Web site that is provided, in whole or in part, by a third party service provider. You can usually identify such third party functionality by the use of a trademark not owned by Room & Board on or near the functionality. In that case, when you use the functionality, you become subject to the terms of use and privacy policy of this third party in addition to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use of our Web site. In some cases, you may need to visit that party's web site and locate the terms of use and privacy policy. For example, we may use a third party to provide you with the opportunity to review our products or services or to upload photographs to our Web site. The reviews and photos you submit may be publicly posted on our Web site or used for other purposes. We currently use Curalate, Inc. to provide the photograph upload capability. You may be required to agree to Curalate's terms of use before you are permitted to upload a photograph to our Web site. When you upload a photograph to our Web site, Curalate is storing your photograph and collecting and storing the information you provide when you upload the photo. For information about Curalate's privacy practices, please review Curalate's Privacy Policy located at <https://www.curalate.com/privacy-policy/>. 

We may also use a third party technology that allows you to chat with Room & Board representatives via our Web site ("Web Chat"). We currently use LivePerson, Inc. to provide the Web Chat capability. When you participate in a Web Chat, LivePerson, Inc. is collecting and storing your chat data. For information about LivePerson's privacy practices, please review LivePerson's Technology Privacy Policy (also known as LivePerson's Customer Website Privacy Policy) located on the [www.liveperson.com](http://www.liveperson.com/) website. 

We may also use cookies, pixel tags, action tags and similar tags to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that is placed on your computer when you visit a web site. A persistent cookie stores information so when you end a session visiting a web site and return to the same web site at a later date the cookie information is still available. Cookies and tags allow us to compile statistics and other information about how you use our site. We may use this data to personalize your Web shopping experience based on your prior visits to our Web site. We may also use this data to analyze trends and improve the usability of our site as well as to administer the site and gather broad demographic statistics. We may also share such non-personally identifiable information with third parties on an aggregate basis. 

In addition, we may use third-party service providers to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Web site, and your interaction with our products and services. They may use cookies and other online tools such as pixel tags, action tags and similar tags to serve ads and personalize your Web shopping experience based on your prior visits to our Web site. They may also use information about your visits to our Web site and other Web sites to target advertisements for products and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a cookie. No personally identifiable information is collected or used in this process. These third-party service providers do not know your name, phone number, address, email address, or any other personally identifying information about you. If you would like more information about this practice and to opt out of having this anonymous information used by our third party service providers, visit the [ Network Advertising Initiative's Consumer Opt-out page ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

Our site responds to a web browser's block of persistent cookies by refraining from using our anonymous cookie. 

Our site may contain links to other Internet web sites that we think you may find of interest. We are not responsible for the content of these sites, nor do we control, sponsor, endorse or approve them. Your use of those links is at your own risk. 

## Sweepstakes

We may offer sweepstakes from time to time. The official rules for our sweepstakes will be made available on our Web site. A sweepstakes may offer furniture for children, but sweepstakes are only open to legal residents of the United States, excluding Rhode Island, and the District of Columbia who are at least 18 years old at the time of entry. 

By entering into a sweepstakes, you provide your personal information, including, but not limited to, first and last name, address, city, state, zip code, and valid email address, to Room & Board and third parties who are specified in the rules for each sweepstakes, and you agree to receive communications from Room & Board and such third parties regarding the sweepstakes you enter. The personal information you provide to Room & Board will be treated in accordance with this privacy policy. The personal information you provide to third parties specified in the sweepstakes rules will be treated in accordance with third parties' privacy policies. Room & Board is not responsible for third party's use of information submitted in connection with a sweepstakes. If you do not agree to Room & Board's Privacy Policy or the privacy policy of third parties to whom personal information is submitted in connection with a sweepstakes, then do not enter the sweepstakes and do not submit your personal information to Room & Board or the applicable third parties. 

## Referrals

We offer an option on our Web site for you to refer candidate(s) to us for consideration for employment. We collect the name, telephone number, and email address of the person who refers a candidate to us, and the name, telephone number, and email address of the candidate. 

We may choose, but are under no obligation, to contact the referred candidate via telephone or email. We have no obligation to hire the referred candidate, and we make no representations about the potential employment of the referred candidate. If a candidate you referred is hired, we will contact you to arrange delivery of a gift card at the telephone number and/or email address you provided in the form on our Web site that you submitted to refer the candidate to us. You are responsible for submitting accurate contact information. 

## Opting out of Room & Board Communications

We will send you communications, including emails, relating to completion of purchase transaction(s) such as order confirmation and shipping information. If you request to receive promotional advertising from us either online or by hard copy such as an in store request or by telephone, you have given us permission to communicate with you about that promotional advertising either by postal mail, e-mail or telephone. Further, if you are engaged in transactions with one of our associates, and choose to use e-mail or telephone for communications about that transaction, you have given us permission to communicate with you about that transaction. Separately, we may send you commercial communications that promote a commercial product or service and may target such communications based on behavior, geographic location, wish list or cart activity, for example. You may opt-out of receiving future commercial communications from us by following the instructions at the bottom of each commercial email you receive, or visit the following URL: [www.roomandboard.com/unsubscribe/](https://www.roomandboard.com/unsubscribe/) or you can also call our Customer Care telephone line at [800.301.9720](tel:1-800-301-9720) to be removed from either our email or postal mail lists. 

We love to send you our annual catalog but only if you want it. Because of that, we've joined Catalog Choice, an organization that lets consumers indicate which catalogs they no longer wish to receive. If you would prefer to not receive our catalogs in the postal mail, or if you are receiving extra copies that you do not need, please visit [catalogchoice.org](http://www.catalogchoice.org/). 

## Correcting or updating your information

Click the following link to correct, change or update your personally identifiable information for the Web site account: [www.roomandboard.com/account/](https://www.roomandboard.com/account/details.do). 

## Notice to California Customers – Your California Privacy Rights:

California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code Section 1798.83, gives California residents the right to ask companies once a year what personal information they share with third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes. If applicable, this information would include the categories of personal information defined in that law, and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared personal information for the immediately prior calendar year. 

If you would like to ask for information under the “Shine the Light” law, please send an email request to our Privacy Officer (see below) with "Request for California Privacy Information" in the subject to help us appropriately identify your question. Please include your mailing address and state of residence so we can provide a response. 

## Privacy Officer

Please direct any questions or comments regarding our Privacy Policy to the office of our Privacy Officer: 

Privacy Officer  
Room & Board, Inc.  
4600 Olson Memorial Highway  
Minneapolis, Minnesota 55422  
phone: 763.588.7525  
e-mail: [privacyofficer@roomandboard.com](mailto:privacyofficer@roomandboard.com)

_Last updated: December 12, 2017_
